## Daehwa Kim

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, exploring a seamless integration of a computer and human that makes new and pleasant experiences. My prior research lies in (a) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs and (b) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

Sensing Techniques	novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated <b>hand inputs</b>	sensing and interaction techniques for a <b>mobile device</b>
for <b>Fluid Interfaces</b>	<ul><li>AtaTouch (Cond. Accepted CHI'21) +</li><li>MagTouch (CHI'20)</li></ul>	<ul><li>OddEyeCam (UIST'20)</li><li>OmniSense (Ongoing)</li></ul>

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **KAIST**, School of Computing

Mar 2019 – Feb 2021 (Expected)

- M.S. student at Human-Computer Interaction Lab
  - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
  - Focus: Sensing Techniques
  - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)
    - o Thesis Committee: Geehyuk Lee (Chair), Juho Kim, Uichin Lee

#### **UNIST**, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
  - B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
  - Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
  - Entered with top honors.
  - · Graduated with Magna Cum Laude
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

#### Jul 2018

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### CONFERENCES

- [1] Daehwa Kim, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" To Appear in Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper, To Appear) Honorable Mention Award
- [2] Daehwa Kim, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [3] Keunwoo Park, Daehwa Kim, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings* of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

#### RESEARCH **EXPERIENCE**

#### HCI Lab, KAIST

Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing

Mar 2018 – Jun 2018

- Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
- Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
- · Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping

#### Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

- Research Intern, IoT Research Division
  - Project: Smart Home project Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice
  - · Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim
  - Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing

#### iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST

- Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering

  - · Project: Finger Joystick Interaction
  - Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

Jan 2018 - Mar 2018

• Focus: human-computer interaction, visualization

# AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

#### Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021

Mar 2021

<u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return-Loss" To Appear in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan.

#### Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing

Feb 2021

 Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras"

#### 4th Prize, NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award

Dec 2017

- Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction".
- Awarded by NAVER CEO.
- Received an award of 1,000,000 KRW.

#### Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016

Dec 2016

- Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to university students.
- Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency.
- Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1.

#### Dean's List, UNIST

■ 2017 Fall Dean's List: GPA 4.05/4.3	Jan 2018
<ul> <li>2017 Spring Dean's List: GPA 3.98/4.3</li> </ul>	Jul 2017
<ul> <li>2016 Fall Dean's List: GPA 3.90/4.3</li> </ul>	Feb 2016
<ul> <li>2016 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.06/4.3</li> </ul>	Aug 2016
■ 2015 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.00/4.3	Jul 2015
Uni-Star Scholarshin UNIST	Mar 2015 - Feb 2019

#### **Uni-Star Scholarship**, UNIST

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

• Entered with top honors.

■ Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester.

#### Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST

Jun 2018

• Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London

### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

# Teaching Assistant, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNISTSep 2018 − Dec 2018Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNISTFeb 2017 − Dec 2017Instructor, Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT)Jul 2016 − Sep 2016Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016

#### ACADEMIC SERVICE

#### Reviewer

■ CHI '21 LBW

#### CAMPUS ACTIVITIES

#### D2 factory, NAVER

Campus Partner
 Hosted the 2nd Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE

#### HeXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST

• A computer security & development research group

Vice-President
 Head of Android development team
 Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members

Feb 2016 – Feb 2017
Feb 2017 – Dec 2017

#### **UNIST Media Center**, UNIST

■ Video Editor Mar 2015 – Feb 2017

Representative work

- My Age 22 Travel to Europe with a drone
- Web drama: The town where engineers live

#### PROJECTS

#### Audio Hero

Sep 2019 – Dec 2019

- Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model
- Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing

**VRone** Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

■ 3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone

• Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming System Light 2.0 @ ETRI Jan 2018 - Mar 2018 • Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing **VibCat** Oct 2017 – Dec 2017 • Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction Skills: Machine learning, Android programming Finger joystick interaction Feb 2017 - Nov 2017 • Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen • Skills: Machine learning, Android programming Poem a moment Mar 2017 - Jun 2017 • An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper Available on Google Play store (download 1000+) Skills: Android programming **TUIT Android Lecture** Jun 2016 - Sep 2016 • Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students • Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming Jun 2016 - Jul 2016

Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way

Available on Google Play store (download 500+)

Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2021-03-15 for Acme Corporation]